Yeah! Hey! Let's go!
好 喂 快走
Watch out!
小心
Are you okay?! Hey?!
你没事吧？喂？
-Yes, I'm fine. -You sure? See ya, then.
-我没事 -你确定？那回见
-Hey. -Huh?
-嘿 -嗯？
You should report it to the police.
你应该报警
You're fine, right?
你没事吧？
-Yes. -Okay.
-没事 -好
If you don't, you might get arrested.
不报警的话 可能会被逮捕
What?
什么？
This should do.
应该报警
"I'm enjoying a cruise today."
“今天享受着邮轮之旅
"Even a lawyer, who continues to fight, needs a moment to rest his wings."
持续奋战的律师也需要片刻 让双翅能够稍事休息”
USHIO LAW FIRM
（潮法律事务所）
What?
怎么了？
Oh, sorry to call you in the middle of the night.
抱歉 大半夜打电话给你
Chief. Is something wrong?
所长 怎么了？
Actually, we just got a request for defense counsel.
其实 我们刚收到辩护律师的请求
Right.
对
Do you think you can take it?
你觉得你可以接受吗？
I'll support you, of course.
我当然会支持你
-Yes, sure. -Oh, thank you.
-好 当然可以 -谢谢…
So, here are the details.
详情是这样的
-In front of that. -Right here.
-在那前面 -就是这里
The day before yesterday, on July 22nd, at around 12:30 at night.
前天 也就是7月22日 半夜12点半左右
Ms. Kazuna Domae
堂前一奈小姐
was driving her electric scooter from her part-time job to her home.
从兼职的地方骑电动代步车回家
When she dodged past the parked van on the road,
在经过路边停车的面包车时
a man came out from behind the van and they crashed.
一名男性从车辆后方冲出来 她就撞上去了
Kazuna rushed over to the man who fell on the ground
一奈小姐凑近倒在地上的男性
and asked, "Are you hurt? I'll call the police and ambulance."
并且问他：“受伤了吗？ 我来叫警察和救护车”
But the man said, "I'm fine. You don't have to do anything," and left.
但男的却说：“我没事 不用了” 就离开了
So she couldn't get his contact information and came home.
没和对方交换联系方式 她就这样回家了
That's what she said.
我妹妹是这么说的
But yesterday, she got worried and went to the police.
不过昨天她说还是很担心 就去找警察询问
There, she was told that the man had fallen unconscious
结果警方告诉她 对方昏迷不醒
and she was arrested on the spot.
当场就把她逮捕了
Yes.
是的
The victim, Mr. Takanobu Shinjo, had walked home.
受害者新庄隆信先生自己步行回家
After a brief conversation with his wife,
和妻子简短交谈过后
his condition suddenly changed and he lost consciousness.
身体状况突然发生变化 失去了意识
His diagnosis was hypoxic encephalopathy caused by fat embolism.
经诊断为 脂肪栓塞造成的缺氧性脑病变
After that, his wife reported it to the police
之后他妻子报警
and they were looking for the culprit.
他们开始寻找真凶
The police seem to think that
警方似乎认为
you left the scene without doing anything to help.
在发生事故后 你什么都没做就离开现场
If so, it's a violation of the duty of care and report.
这样的话 就构成了 违反救助义务和报告义务
Basically, a hit-and-run--
也就是所谓的肇事逃逸…
I didn't hit and run!
我没有肇事逃逸
He really said he was fine.
那个人真的说他没事
Right.
好吧
That's what we'll be arguing in court, so I'm confirming it now.
这就是我们在法庭上要辩论的 所以我现在正在确认
Under today's law, electric scooters are treated the same as mopeds.
根据现行法律 电动代步车等同于轻型代步车
Causing serious injury to someone you crashed into…
对你撞到的人造成严重伤害…
Someone you crashed into
你撞到的人
and if that turned out to be a hit-and-run,
如果案件变成肇事逃逸
you could be sentenced to prison for several years.
你会被判入狱数年
You have a driving license, of course, and liability insurance too.
你当然有驾照 也投保了强制责任险
But not the optional one.
但没有第三责任险
Ah, I see.
原来如此
I'm sorry about this.
很抱歉
I called you without thinking.
我想都没想就打给你
-No problem. -It's an honor that you remembered us.
-没关系 -很荣幸你推荐了我们
That's right.
没错
I'm surprised you remembered an old man like me.
你推荐我这样的老头子 我很惊讶
You really helped us during the accident two years ago.
两年前的事故你真的帮了我们大忙
Oh, no. I only helped you claim for damages.
没有啦 我只在损害赔偿方面 稍微帮了一点忙而已
Right?
对吗？
Thanks to you, the insurance company paid the full amount.
多亏有你相助 保险公司才会全额赔偿
I'm glad I was able to help.
能帮上忙 我也很高兴
My little sister and I managed to get by because of that money.
因为有那笔钱 我和妹妹才能撑过来
Well, you two lost both your parents and you lost your eyesight in that accident.
你们因为那起车祸失去了爸妈 你甚至丧失了视力
So I wanted to do what I could for you both.
我只是想尽力帮帮你们俩
Here.
请用
Thank you very much.
不好意思 谢谢你
Mr. Haneoka will also support you too.
羽根冈律师也会全力帮忙的
Thank you.
谢谢
I'll take the civil case.
民事的部分交给我
Mr. Haneoka will handle the criminal case.
羽根冈律师会负责刑事案件
He'll try and get a settlement without punishment.
他会尽力争取和解 不施加惩罚
Get off already.
可以下来了
Honestly, I avoided these because I didn't want to be a bandwagoner…
说真的 我以为骑这东西的人 都很轻浮 一直敬而远之…
I can't hear a word he's blabbing on about.
他好像说了什么 但我完全听不到
The 30-minute free ride will be over if he doesn't hurry.
他再不快点 30分钟免费试骑的时间就要结束了
And what am I here for?
那我要做什么？
Oh, I'm sorry.
不好意思
I wanted you to help us look for witnesses.
我想要请你帮忙找目击证人
-Okay. -Yes.
-好
What about checking the security camera?
要不要看看监控？
We asked around earlier, but they all declined.
我们之前就打听过 但他们都拒绝了
While submission of footage to the police is an obligation, it's not to lawyers.
虽然向警方提交监控录像是一项义务 但对律师则不然
So, we're going to search the hard way until the time of the accident.
我们只能用笨办法去搜索 直到案发之前
Hey, hey, hey.
喂
-Don't just drive past us. Get off. -No.
-不要若无其事地骑过去 下车 -不要
We're returning it within the free--
必须在免费试骑的时段内还车…
They're so close.
感情真好
Stingy Ms. Ishiko.
吝啬的石田小姐
By the way, about that swept-back hair.
对了 关于你的后卷头发
Is that from your genius memo, "A unique hairstyle might be good"?
这是出自你的天才备忘录吗？ “独特的发型可能会很好”？
There's no problem, right?
这样不会有什么问题吧
I told you, there's no need to act like a genius anymore.
早就告诉你了 没必要表现得跟天才似的
This is my weapon.
这是我的武器
I think you're totally straying from your plan.
我觉得你完全偏离计划了
Get off!
下车
He's fully conscious and we're told he won't have any aftereffects.
他完全清醒了 而且我们被告知他不会有任何后遗症
Ma'am.
女士
I have a letter for you from the suspect's sister.
我有封信要交给你 是受害人的妹妹写的
I didn't agree to meet you because I wanted an apology.
我不同意见你 因为我想要一个道歉
I just want to clarify what she put my husband through.
我只是想澄清她让我丈夫经历了什么
He said…
他说…
he was hit by an electric scooter
他是被电动代步车撞到的
and the driver just left him there and fled the scene.
骑车的人扔下他不管 逃离了现场
But the suspect said she helped him up.
但嫌疑人说她帮助他站起来了
The police told me there's no proof of that.
警方告诉我没有相关证据
If she had reported immediately, none of this would've happened.
要是她立刻报警 这种事情就不会发生了
Could our client be lying?
会不会是委托人在说谎？
Well, I'd hate to think so.
我不愿意这样想
-I wanted to offer a settlement. -Huh? Yoshio?
-原本还想提和解的… -佳男？
Hello, Ms. Ishida.
你好 石田小姐
Good afternoon.
下午好
Why are you here? Are you unwell?
你为什么在这里？身体不舒服吗？
Same reason as you.
理由跟你一样
I've been assigned to take over the electric scooter case.
电动代步车的案子改由我来负责了
I'm glad you're the defense lawyer. It'll spare unnecessary hardships.
辩护律师是你真是太好了 我就不用那么辛苦了
What do you mean?
什么意思？
You heard that the victim doesn't want a settlement, right?
受害者无意和解 你知道吧？
I'll be prosecuting for negligent driving resulting in injury
我会以驾驶过失伤害罪 和违反照护义务
and violation of duty of care.
起诉她
I'm also in charge of the trial, so I'll see you in court.
公审也是由我负责 法庭上见
Bye.
再见
First of all, there's no dashboard camera on this parked van.
首先 停在路边的面包车 没有行车记录仪
This is security camera footage from the area.
这是附近监控的画面
Here is the victim.
这是受害者
And this is the defendant.
这是被告
As you can see, the victim is walking beside the van.
如各位所见 受害者走到面包车旁
And the defendant on the electric scooter drives up.
这时被告也骑着电动代步车过来了
They seemed to have collided here.
就是这时候发生碰撞的
The moment is not captured on camera.
这个瞬间并没有被摄像头拍到
This means there's no proof she has offered any assistance.
换句话说 没有证据能证明 被告曾试图提供任何救助
Rather, considering the time until she left the scene,
另外 考虑到被告离开现场的时间
it's reasonable to think that she did not do anything.
认为她什么也没做也是合理的
As you can tell from the earlier footage,
从刚刚的监控视频也可以得知
the victim was trying to cross the road with no pedestrian crossing.
受害者是从没有人行横道的地方 横穿马路
Additionally, there are many parked cars at night.
加上夜间路边停了很多车
As it is difficult to foresee a pedestrian rushing out from behind them,
要预见行人从车辆后方冲出来 是很困难的
it should be considered that the victim had also been negligent.
应该也要考虑受害者是否有过失
Although this is a legal precedent from a civil case, there was a case
虽然是民事案件的判例 不过以前也发生过
with similar circumstances to this one
跟本案类似的情况
where the level of negligence for the offender was judged to be very low.
最后判决加害者的过失程度非常低
Lastly, two years ago,
最后 你是在两年前
you've lost your parents in a traffic accident, correct?
一场交通事故中失去了双亲吧？
Yes.
对
Did that change or influence your awareness toward driving?
那件影响到你对驾驶的心态吗？
Yes. I've followed the legal speed limit
对 我一直遵守法定速限
and made sure to drive safely so I won't cause an accident.
也总是注意行车安全 避免造成交通意外
You've never committed traffic violations nor lied to the police, correct?
你不曾因违反交通规则而被捕 或是对警方说谎吧？
Correct. I haven't.
对 我没有
Very well. That'll be all.
我知道了 没有其他问题了
Prosecutor, your cross-examination.
检方请进行交叉讯问
Yes.
好的
Let me get to the point.
那我就开门见山了
Don't you have a juvenile record involving a traffic violation?
你在未成年的时候 不是曾经涉及违反交通规则的案子？
Four years ago, when you were 17,
四年前 你17岁的时候
you rode double on a bicycle with a man you were dating then and hit a pedestrian.
和当时交往的男性骑自行车双载 与行人发生碰撞
And you two fled the scene without reporting it.
当时你并没有报警 而是和那名男性一同逃逸
A witness reported the accident later and you were arrested.
后来有目击者报案 你们才被逮捕
Am I wrong?
我有说错吗？
You're right.
没错
Do you remember what you said back then?
你还记得当时被逮捕时 你说了什么吗？
You said you had no recollection of the accident,
你说你不记得这件事了
but you admitted to lying after learning there was security camera footage. Right?
但是知道有监视器画面之后 你就承认说谎了 不是吗？
Yes.
对
She said she's never committed a traffic violation nor has she lied to the police.
她刚刚说从来没有违反交通规则 也不曾对警方说谎
But that is clearly a lie.
很明显是伪证
The defendant's testimony has no credibility.
被告的供词一点可信度也没有
She probably thought she wouldn't be trusted
她应该是担心要是坦承有前科
if she told you about her juvenile record.
你们就不会相信她了吧
We managed to secure one more opportunity to question the defendant.
我们已经争取到 再次进行被告讯问的机会了
Thank you very much.
谢谢
She may not be able to avoid prison sentencing.
这样应该是免不了要入狱服刑了
What if this wasn't a hit-and-run?
如果不是肇事逃逸呢？
Well, his injury wasn't so serious after all,
就结果而言 受害者的伤势并不严重
so it will be completely different.
判决结果会完全不一样
Should we focus on finding witnesses?
我们来全力寻找目击证人吧？
Something isn't right.
有点不对劲
My sister is the leading young star in the Public Prosecutors Office.
我姐是东京地检 年轻检察官里的头号王牌
She's not in the traffic department
况且她又不隶属于交通部
and it's not like her to take on traffic accident cases.
印象中也没负责过这类交通案件
And yet, why her?
怎么会改由她负责？
The electric scooter is a new vehicle,
电动代步车 这种新型交通工具变得普及
which is becoming more common, so maybe they're proceeding cautiously.
所以这次的案件检方可能会谨慎对待
I see.
原来如此
Hmm…
嗯…
Hello. This is Ushio Law Firm.
你好 这里是潮法律事务所
I'm Shinjo's wife.
我是新庄的太太
Yes. How may we help you?
是 请问有什么事吗？
My husband said he's willing to consider a settlement.
我先生说他愿意考虑和解
If she pleads guilty in court
只要她在法庭上诚实认罪
and pays 10 million yen immediately, I'll consider it.
同时立即赔偿一千万日圆 我可以考虑和解
I'm sorry, but that amount may be a little difficult.
不好意思 这个金额可能有点困难
How much were you expecting?
你们打算要赔多少钱？
It'll take a little time since she doesn't have optional coverage,
她没有投保第三人责任险 没办法马上算出来
but 2 million yen plus medical expenses and compensation for absence--
不过除了医药费和所失利益的赔偿 大概是两百万日圆…
Do you really get it?
有没有搞清楚状况？
I almost died because of the hit-and-run.
她肇事逃逸 我差点就没命了
Yes, Ms. Kazuna Domae is also very sorry--
是 关于这一点 堂前一奈小姐也感到非常抱歉…
Enough of your lip service.
不要再讲这些漂亮话了
I won't be able to go back to work for a long time.
我有很长一段时间没办法回去工作
If she seems sincere, I'll testify that I don't wish for her to be punished.
如果感受到她的诚意 我会出庭作证 表示不希望她被判刑
But if she continues to lie,
但如果她继续说谎
all I hope for her is severe punishment.
只会让我希望她受到严惩
How can I prepare that much money…
这么一大笔钱 要去哪里准备…
We understand.
我们理解
If I sell this house…
如果把这个房子卖掉
Then, I can pay it.
应该就付得出来
I guess… you're right.
我想…你说得对
Yes.
对
If your lives can be protected by paying the settlement…
只要付出和解金 就能确保你俩的生活
This house is filled with memories of our parents, but…
虽然这个家充满 我们跟父母一起生活的回忆
But if it can protect Kazuna.
但只要能保护一奈
No way!
绝对不行
Why should I pay 10 million yen to a liar?
我为什么要付一千万给那个骗子？
I swear that Shinjo guy is lying!
那个叫新庄的人真的在说谎
I really ran up to him…
我过去问他…
Oh, yeah. Back then, I smelled a sweet and sour odor on him.
对了 那时候 我在他身上闻到一股酸酸甜甜的气味
Sweet and sour odor?
酸酸甜甜的气味
Isn't that proof?
这不是靠近过他的证据吗？
Not with your testimony alone.
光靠你单方面的证词有点困难
We may be able to use it if we can prove
如果能证明那天 新庄先生身上真的有那股气味
Mr. Shinjo definitely had that odor on him that day, but…
或许就另当别论了 不过…
Oh, I have something for you from your sister.
对了 你姐要我们转交东西给你
She knows you're sensitive to the cold.
她知道你手脚容易冰冷
Here you go.
麻烦你了
I'll check it.
我检查一下
Thank you.
谢谢
Why would she…
姐姐为什么…
Our apologies, but we're unable to pay the amount you suggest--
对不起 我们付不出你要求的金额…
Then…
那么…
I'll go all out to claim the compensation in the civil trial.
我会在民事法庭上全力争取赔偿金额
By the way…
顺便请教一下
what were you doing there at that time on the day of the accident?
事发当天的那个时间 你在那个地方做什么呢？
It seems pretty far from your workplace--
那里离你的职场好像很远…
I don't have to answer that.
我没有义务要回答你吧
Honey.
孩子的爸
You have a call.
你的电话
Hello?
喂？
What if he gets upset? What's bugging you?
他要是生气的话怎么办？ 你为何在意那件事？
I wonder what the sweet and sour odor is.
那个酸酸甜甜的气味到底是什么
Who knows if she really smelled it.
谁知道她是不是真的闻到了
She could be lying again.
说不定又在说谎
We don't know what the smell is to begin with.
再说了 我们根本不知道那气味是什么
They should pay even if they had to sell their house.
果然应该把房子卖掉 拿去付和解金的
If all goes well, she may get a suspended senten--
只要受害者在法庭上说不希望严惩 说不定就有机会判缓刑…
Really?
真的吗？
If the client says that's not the truth, I think we should fight.
我认为如果委托人说另有实情 就应该争取到底
But we have no proof.
但就没有任何证据
So we should try and find the proof--
所以只要继续努力寻找证据…
-You know I hate wasting time. -L.E.!
-你知道我讨厌浪费时间 -律伦
Unbelievable!
真不敢相信
Did you reach a settlement?
怎么样 达成和解了吗？
No.
没有
I see.
这样啊
You don't change, huh?
你还是一成不变吧？
You still fight like that?
还在采取那样的应战方式？
If you can't be flexible, it's over. You get that?
没办法随机应变就完了 懂吗？
Clients' lives depend on your competency.
你这么不成熟 只会让委托人变得不幸
Are you determined enough for that?
你真的有背负他人人生的决心吗？
If you aren't, you should quit being a lawyer.
没有的话 还是别当律师比较好
You may be family, but that's--
就算是家人 也说得太过分…
Being too soft on your family is also debatable, isn't it?
对自己人太过宽容 是会出问题的 不是吗？
Take a look at this.
你们看
The father of the victim's wife, Wakaba Shinjo,
受害者妻子新庄和可叶小姐的父亲
was the chief prosecutor in Tokyo.
是东京地检的前检察长
Maybe this is the reason Mr. Haneo's sister was assigned.
这或许是羽根冈律师的姐姐 负责这个案子的原因
It's possible.
有可能
In other words, the victim is related to the prosecution side
也就是说 受害者是检方的自己人
and he might be under silent pressure.
可能因此受到无形压力
Yes.
对
When your sister said, "Being too soft on your family,"
该不会 你姐说的 “对自己人太过宽容”
could she mean the prosecutors?
指的就是检方吧？
I don't know about that.
我不知道
I'm gonna go home.
我要回家了
Bye.
再见
See you tomorrow.
明天见
See you.
回见
USHIO LAW FIRM
（潮法律事务所）
The key is over there.
钥匙在那里
Yeah, I know.
对 我知道
What?
怎么了？
Apparently, they don't eat natto.
他们明显不吃纳豆
Huh?
什么？
The people who work in sake breweries don't eat natto during the brewing period.
在酿酒厂工作的人再怎么喜欢纳豆 在酿酒期间都不会吃
What's this about?
你在说什么？
It's to prevent the natto bacteria
这是为了避免纳豆菌
from killing the microorganisms that the sake needs.
杀死酿造清酒所需的微生物
Doesn't knowing that make you want to drink sake?
知道这件事 不会让你想喝日本酒吗？
Is that an invitation?
这是在邀请我去喝一杯吗？
Yes.
对
It's so hard to tell…
这么拐弯抹角…
You drink fast.
你喝得好快
Do I?
是吗？
Here's your itawasa.
这是芥末鱼板
Thank you.
谢谢
Looks good.
看起来很美味
I thought it might be necessary for us to get to know each other
我认为我们伙伴之间
as partners, once in a while.
还是应该偶尔联络一下感情
Partners? That's an exaggeration.
伙伴？太夸张了
Is that so.
是吗？
If you're trying to cheer me up,
如果你是想要鼓励我
I'm not bothered.
我并不在意
By her words, I mean.
那个人说的话
Here's tamagoyaki.
煎蛋卷来了
Man, I'm exhausted.
真是累坏了
Excuse me.
不好意思
-May I? -Hey…
-可以吗？ -喂…
Since there aren't other customers around, maybe I'll drink too.
没其他客人了 我也来喝一杯
What?
什么？
So, how's it going?
最近怎么样？
How? What is?
怎么样？你是指什么？
You know, like everything.
就…泛指一切
How is it going?
怎么样？
-That's so vague. -You don't have to--
-太笼统了 -不用非得…
-So good. -The bubbles.
-好喝 -泡泡喷出来了
Sorry about that.
不好意思
Please clean up.
麻烦你收拾一下桌面
-You're like a crab. -Mom, clean up!
-你好像螃蟹 -妈 收拾一下
It's not your mom's job.
不应该叫你妈收吧
You're going fast.
你走得真快
Oh, am I?
会吗？
Walking helps when you're trying to figure things out.
心烦的时候 散散步会有帮助
It clears your mind, doesn't it?
可以让你理清思绪 对吧？
Even if you can't find the answer if you keep walking,
即使一时找不到答案 只要一直走下去
you'll definitely find something one day.
总有一天会找到什么的
Are you sure it's alright
新庄隆信先生的证词
to fully trust Mr. Takanobu Shinjo's testimony?
确定要全然听信吗？
Maybe we should've been more careful.
应该要更慎重调查才对吧
Better bend than break.
做事要有弹性
Oh, I heard. The opposing lawyer is your brother, right?
我听说了 对方的辩护律师是你弟弟吧？
Don't go easy on him.
别轻易放过他
Of course not.
当然不会
You know how I am, don't you?
你了解我的 对吧？
My bad.
是我的错
Hello, it's Ishida.
你好 我是石田
-Hello.
-你好
Thank you.
谢谢
-Hey, you. -How are you?
-嘿 -你好吗？
"Thank you for taking care of my sister."
“谢谢你照顾我姐姐
"Could you help her renew the fire insurance?"
可以请你帮忙续保火灾保险吗？
"You can find the contacts in the right top drawer of my desk."
联系方式放在我的书桌右边 最上面的抽屉里
"Also…
还有…
she tends to overeat sweet things so please keep an eye on her."
我姐喜欢吃一大堆甜食 请帮我盯着她 别让她吃太多”
Cheeky.
真顽皮
Alexa, turn on the air conditioner.
亚历莎 开下空调
Yes.
好
What happened to your arm?
你的手臂怎么了？
I went to see Mr. Shinjo.
我去见了新庄先生
At the hospital?
去医院吗？
Yes. Yesterday, with my friend.
是的 昨天和朋友一起去的
But he refused to see me.
不过他拒绝见我
Next time, please let us know.
下次请告诉我们一声
Mr. Shinjo is also a witness for the criminal case,
新庄先生也是刑事诉讼的证人
so contacting him impulsively could worsen our position.
擅自跟他接触恐怕对我方不利
I'm sorry.
对不起
I want to prove that my sister isn't lying.
我就想证明我妹妹没有说谎
-No one's home? -No.
-没人在家吗？ -没有
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Asking this person.
问那个人
He's sleeping. Hey…
他在睡觉…
Oh, it's so cool.
好凉
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Hello.
你好
These are the documents you asked for.
这是你要的资料
Thank you very much. A suit?
非常感谢 西装？
For a job interview.
我要去面试工作
Now?
现在吗？
They made time for me.
他们说我可以做完兼职再过去
I see.
这样啊
I'll join the witness search after the interview.
今晚的查访 等面试结束 我也会加入的
No, you should get some rest today.
今天就不用了
But late-night investigation is dangerous.
但那么晚了还去调查会很危险
I'll be fine.
没事的
But I can go.
但我可以去
But I feel bad.
但我觉得过意不去
Please hear me out.
请听我把话说完
Huh?
什么？
This is when I was in high school. On the first Monday of April.
是高中时的事了 那是四月的第一个星期一
Right.
对
There was a lady on a train in a suit. It was probably her first day at work.
在电车上 我前面有位穿着西装套装 看起来像新进职员的女生
She's mumbling a speech written on a note.
手上拿着自我介绍的笔记 嘴里一直念念有词
But she had a tag from the dry cleaners.
但她套装上的干洗标签没拿掉
Okay.
好吧
I thought she's probably introducing herself today.
她应该是第一天上班要自我介绍
And I felt bad because she had that tag on her suit.
但是套装上还留着标签 感觉很不好
But I didn't have the courage to tell her and she got off the train.
但我没有勇气告诉她 她就这样下车了
I still think about it after ten years.
十年过去了 我还是会想起这件事
My point is,
我想说的是
I'm the kind of guy who'd always regret not doing anything
明明可以采取行动避免那种状况 我却什么也没做
when I could've prevented it.
我就会一直耿耿于怀
So, if I didn't do anything knowing that you could be in trouble,
所以 明知你说不定会遇到危险
it will haunt me for the rest of my life.
我却什么也没做的话 真的会一辈子都很后悔
So, I'll come!
所以我会去
Okay.
好
Huh?
什么？
If that's the case…
那样的话
Please come.
就一起去吧
Sure.
好啊
Are you not late?
不会迟到吧？
Oh, crap. I'll see you later.
糟糕 回见吧
Mr. Oba.
大庭先生
Good luck!
祝你好运
Excuse me, have you seen this man?
不好意思 请问你见过这个人吗？
Oh, this guy.
这个人啊
You know him?
你认识他吗？
He bumped into me. I think he was pretty drunk.
他好像喝得烂醉 结果撞到了我
He left without apologizing.
也没道歉就离开了
Do you remember when that was?
你记得是什么时候的事吗？
Um, it was July 22nd.
那天呢 是7月22日
Are you sure?
没记错吗？
Yeah, I was in a hurry that day for my daughter's birthday.
那天是我女儿生日 所以我赶着回去
Was there anything else you noticed about him?
请问你还注意到什么事吗？
The smell? He had this strong sweet and sour odor like an apple.
有味道？像苹果一样 酸酸甜甜的味道猛然传过来
Do you know which direction he came from?
你知道他是从哪个方向走过来吗？
Yeah, from back there.
从那后面
Actually, I've been wondering where Mr. Shinjo came from all this time
其实我一直很在意 新庄先生是从哪里走到现场的
and I've been checking out the stores in this area.
所以调查过这附近的店家
And one of them stood out.
其中有一家很让我在意
That's the entrance.
这里就是入口
I'm Ueno, referred here by Mr. Suzuhara.
铃原先生介绍我来的 我叫上野
We've been informed. Welcome.
我们听说了 请进
No.
不行
You'll lose if you don't.
不出拳就算输
Your timing's off.
你的时机不对
Yes?
什么？
We've been referred here by Mr. Takanobu Shinjo.
新庄隆信先生介绍我们过来的
We're Ishida and Haneoka.
我们是石田和羽根冈
Mr. Shinjo, did you say?
新庄先生吗？
Huh? Have you not been informed?
奇怪？你们没听说吗？
He said he'd make the call.
他说会打电话跟店里说一声的
That's strange. Did we get the date wrong?
奇怪？是我们记错日期了吗？
Maybe.
有可能
No, please come in.
不 请进
Ms. Ishida and Mr. Haneoka.
石田小姐和羽根冈先生
Mr. Shinjo referred us here.
新庄先生介绍我们过来的
Yes, welcome.
好 请进
Has he told you about this place?
两位听说过这个地方吗？
Yes, roughly.
大概知道
Betting starts at 30,000.
起价三万日圆
-Oh… -Right…
-哦… -好…
Once you have the chips, you can't redeem them until you win or lose 10,000.
换完筹码之后 除非赢或输了一万日圆才能兑现
Okay.
好
I'll bring your chips now.
我去帮两位准备筹码
-Thank you. -Yes.
-谢谢 -好
Oh!
对了
Do you smoke hookah?
两位要抽水烟吗？
Oh, yes.
好
Very well.
我知道了
Smells like apples.
苹果的味道
This is it.
就是这个了
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-两位客人 -是？
I confirmed with Mr. Shinjo and he doesn't recall referring you.
我跟新庄先生确认过了 他不记得有介绍人过来
I need you to explain yourselves.
我要跟两位确认一下这是怎么回事
-Let's talk-- -We're leaving.
-我们到后面去谈… -我们要离开了…
Sir.
先生
Wait!
等等
-We're leaving. -Wait!
-我们要走了 -站住
-Come back! -Wai--
-等等…
We'll talk to you in the back.
我们到后面谈谈
Hey…
嘿…
Mr. Takanobu Shinjo comes here, right?
新庄先生会来这里 对吧？
Huh?
什么？
Could you testify that he came here on July 22nd?
可以请你出庭作证 他在7月22日来过这里吗？
Shut up!
闭嘴
-Are you crazy? -Please!
-你疯了吗？ -拜托
All we need is for you to testify and--
只要你愿意出庭作证…
-Please! Ouch… -Get in here!
-拜托 哎哟… -进去
Oh, let's not do that.
不要动手
No violence. No fists.
不要使用暴力 不要动拳头
Who the hell are you two?
你们到底是什么人？
I'm a lawyer.
我是律师
Any additional violence--
要是再随便动手的话…
And what?!
那又怎样？
You think that's gonna scare me?!
你以为这样就能吓倒我吗？
Police! Don't move!
警察 全部不许动
We received a tip that this is an illegal casino.
我们接获线报 这里有非法赌场
Show me your ID!
请出示身份证件
Please stop!
不要打了
-Oh. -Come on, get up!
-哦 -快站起来
-Hey… -Ishiko!
-等等… -石子学姐
Don't move, we're the police!
不许动 我们是警察
All of you, don't move!
统统不许动
Oh geez…
天啊…
-Come on, let's go. -Oh, we're not…
-我们走吧 -不是…
-We're not customers here. -We're not.
-我们不是赌客 -我们不是…
Oh, really? We can talk about that later. Okay?
这样吗？总之 我们回局里再聊吧？
-Please wait. -My leg. My leg hurts.
-请等一下 -我的脚 好痛…
Let go!
放开我
He's so energetic.
他活蹦乱跳的
You saved us, Mr. Oba.
你救了我们 大庭先生
Yeah, you really did.
真的是这样
I couldn't wait for the police and I charged in.
我等不及警察赶到就冲进去了
We owe you.
我们欠你个人情
No worries.
别担心
There are no more trains, so let's take a taxi.
已经没有电车了 打车回去吧
-It's on the firm. -Okay.
-可以报账 -好
-Ow, ow…
-哎哟…
-You okay? -You're going the other way, right?
-还好吗？ -大庭先生的家是在反方向吧？
Ah, yes.
还真是
It'll be cheaper if I drop off Mr. Haneoka on my way home.
我送羽根冈律师回去 这样车钱比较便宜
-Okay. -So, you get in.
-好 -上车吧
Please take a good rest.
请回去好好休息吧
I will.
我会的
Good night.
晚安
Hey, good work today.
嘿 今天辛苦了
See you.
回见
-See you. -Please drive.
-回见 -麻烦开车
-Bye. -Take care.
-再见 -保重
One, two. One, two.
一、二、一、二
-Three-legged race, is it? -Make sure you go to the hospital.
-在玩两人三足吗？ -你一定要去医院
I'll get better if I sleep.
没问题的 睡一觉就会好了
-Is this it? Here. -Thanks.
-是这里吗？ -谢谢
Okay then. See you tomorrow.
那好 明天见
Do you contribute to the hometown tax program?
你还继续缴纳故乡税吗？
Excuse me?
什么？
The place I contributed to
我纳税的那个地方
sends me draft beer in return.
回赠生啤
Huh?
什么？
I heard that draft beer is the same as tap beer in Japan.
我听说生啤就是日本的生啤酒
-What about it? -So, you know…
-所以呢？ -因此呢…
Do you wanna join me for a drink?
要不要一起喝一杯？
What?
什么？
Sure.
好
-Can't we drink inside? -No.
-在房间里喝不行吗？ -不行
I can't enter a man's room so casually.
我不会随便进男人的房间
I see.
原来如此
There.
好吧
It's a great view.
景色真漂亮
Yeah.
是的
Actually, I was bothered.
其实我很在意
By my sister's words.
我姐说的那些话
Honestly, I've no confidence.
说实话 我没有自信
Ever since I was little, the only weapon I've had is my memory.
从小我唯一厉害的就只有记忆力
I have this ability called photographic memory,
一种叫做影像记忆的能力
where I can memorize what I see instantly.
看到的东西瞬间就能记下来
I only passed the bar exam because of that ability.
能通过司法考试也是靠这项能力
And also…
而且…
If anything unexpected happens, my body…
只要发生意料之外的事情 我的身体…
Actually…
其实
My father has told me about that.
这件事我爸已经跟我说了
Oh, he has?
是吗？
Is that why you made up that genius character?
所以你才想要塑造天才的角色？
Well…
这个嘛…
Yeah…
是吧
So, I wasn't confident enough to defend this case in court either.
这次的案件也是 我没有自信上了法庭能顺利辩护
That's why I wished for an out-of-court settlement.
所以才想要达成庭外和解
Like my sister said,
就像我姐说的
I think I wasn't determined enough.
应该是决心不够吧
Where's your confidence, Mr. Lawyer?
说那什么丧气话 你这位律师？
Huh?
什么？
You know I've failed the exam four times, right?
你知道我司法考试四次没过吧？
You passed.
你考上了
That should be enough to make you confident.
应该足够让你有自信了吧
You're right.
你说得对
I guess there's always someone beneath you.
比上不足 比下有余
Watch it.
真让我抓狂
It's pretty amazing how you've failed four times.
是说东大法学院名列前茅毕业
-After graduating from Tokyo University. -Enough of that.
-司法考试落榜四次才厉害吧 -这件事就别提了
Okay.
好吧
Let's help them, yeah?
很想帮她们吧？
-We're looking for a witness. -Emi, drink some water.
-我们在找目击者 -绘实 喝点水吧
Did you witness a traffic accident?
我们在找交通事故的目击者
Thank you very much.
谢谢 拜托
We'd appreciate your help.
谢谢 请各位帮忙
It's my little sister!
这是我妹妹
SECOND TRIAL
（第二次公审）
Do you know a building called "Quest" in Onaga town?
你知道尾长町有一栋 名叫“探索”的大楼吗？
No.
不知道
A witness testified that he saw you coming out
我们取得了目击者的证词 他说事发之前
from that building at the concerned time.
看到你从那栋大楼离开
You really don't know?
真的不知道吗？
No.
对
As per the Plaintiff's Exhibit 18, which we just examined,
根据刚刚看过的辩方18号证据
one of the stores in that building allows illegal casino activities.
那栋大楼里有间店在经营非法赌场
Have you not been there?
你没有去那里吗？
No.
没有
Objection.
我有异议
These questions have no relevance to this case.
这些问题跟本案毫无关系
Counsel, what's the purpose of your questions?
辩护律师 你提问的目的是什么？
These are important questions to verify that the witness
这些是很重要的问题 为的是要确认
is not giving a false testimony.
证人是否做了伪证
Objection is overruled.
反对无效
Please continue.
请继续
Thank you.
谢谢
As per the evidence we submitted, that store is filled with hookah smoke.
根据我方提出的证据 这间店里充满了水烟的烟雾
So if you've been there,
在里面待个几分钟
your clothes will pick up its sweet and sour odor within a few minutes.
衣服就会沾染酸甜的气味
The previously mentioned eyewitness
刚刚提到的目击者
and the defendant, who ran up to you after the accident,
以及事故发生后跑到你身边的被告
have testified that they smelled something sweet and sour from you.
都作证在你身上 闻到了酸酸甜甜的香味
Have you not been there?
你真的没有去过那里吗？
No.
对
Are you sure?
真的吗？
If she called an ambulance and the police questioned you,
要是叫了救护车 警察会问你话
people may find out that you're a regular at an illegal casino.
经常出入非法赌场的事情 就可能会曝光
Isn't that why you left the scene?
所以你才急着离开现场 不是吗？
Your honor.
审判长
These statements are circumstantial and unsubstantiated.
这一连串发言 都是根据薄弱的情况证据
These are mere speculations and it's not even a question.
辩护律师只是猜测 根本不算是提问
Counsel should be asking based on facts and not making claims.
辩护律师不要提出自己的主张 请根据事实提问
My apologies.
对不起
Now, to clarify the statement,
那么 为了让陈述更加明确
I'd like to show you the map from Plaintiff's Exhibit 20.
我想出示辩方第20号证据的地图
Go ahead.
请出示
The distance to Supermarket Katsuzen from your home is approximately…
从你家到胜膳超市的距离大约是
four kilometers.
四公里
Is that correct?
没错吧？
Yes.
没错
From the day you started using an electric scooter
从你开始使用电动代步车
until the day of the accident,
到发生事故那天
do you remember how many times you drove to Katsuzen?
你记得去了胜膳超市多少次吗？
We've kept the receipts for household accounts
为了家里记账 收据都有留下来
and it was a total of 24 times.
总共是24次
Okay. That means, a round-trip will be four times two. So, eight kilometers.
好 所以往返的距离是 四公里乘以二 总共八公里
Four times eight…
四八…
Four times eight?
四八是多少？
Four times eight is 32.
四八三十二
So, 160 added to 32 is 192 kilometers.
160加32等于192公里
The round-trip distance to her workplace and the round-trip to the supermarket is
前往兼职地点的来回距离 加上前往超市的来回距离
1,047 kilometers.
总共是1047公里
-May I? -Please!
-我可以发言吗？ -请说
It's not even worth an objection,
这好像连异议都不算
but this is not the place for the defense to make assumptions.
法庭不是让辩护律师 陈述个人想法的地方
Receipts from the supermarket does not prove
再说了 就算保留了超市的收据
that she drove there on an electric scooter in the first place.
也不能证明被告是骑电动代步车去的
She could've walked or ridden a bicycle.
她可能是徒步或骑脚踏车去的
And even if she was using an electric scooter,
就算她是骑电动代步车去的
what does that matter?
那又怎么样？
Assertions based on such weak grounds do not prove anything.
根据这么薄弱的证据提出的主张 根本证明不了什么
It scares me that you think this is good enough evidence.
如果你觉得这样就算是证据 未免也太吓人了
Counsel, we don't need your personal opinion right now.
辩护律师 现在不需要提出你的见解
Please stick to the facts.
请根据事实提问
Can we move on?
你没有问题了吧？
-Oh, I still-- -Enough already.
-不 我还有… -给我差不多一点
Your honor, the defense keeps questioning with unknown purposes
审判长 辩护律师持续提出目的不明的讯问
and is clearly impeding the trial.
很明显是要妨碍诉讼进行
You're right. Counsel, we cannot--
说得也是 辩护律师 到此为止…
No. Um, I still…
不 那个…
Excuse me.
不好意思
-You're late. I'm sweating so much. -Sorry.
-太慢了 我冒了一身冷汗 -抱歉
No personal conversations.
法庭上不要窃窃私语
I apologize.
非常抱歉
The defense has no more questions.
辩方没有其他问题了
Instead…
相反地
I would like to submit a new piece of evidence.
我方想提出新的证据
What is this? We haven't been informed.
怎么回事？之前没听说啊
The defendant's sister, Emi,
被告的姐姐绘实小姐
has been handing out flyers every night for the past two weeks
这两个星期以来 每晚都在发传单
at the time of the accident in search for witnesses.
寻找事发当时的目击者
In order to prove that her little sister,
为了证明一直在照顾自己的妹妹
who's always taken care of her, didn't commit hit-and-run.
并没有肇事逃逸
She did it every day for two weeks.
这两星期都在发传单
And those who sympathized with her posted on social media
受到这个行为感动的人 把消息发到社交网站上
and it caused a buzz on the internet.
在网络上引起热议
A truck driver, who parked
然后 在车祸当天
a little distance away from the scene of the accident,
把车停在事故现场不远处的货车司机
saw the post on social media and contacted us last night.
偶然看到了贴文 在昨晚联系我们
And he said he'd give us the dashboard camera footage.
表示愿意提供行车记录仪的视频
That's what you say.
你就在法庭上表明这一点
Sounds good.
听起来不错
But he was away for delivery, so he couldn't give it to us immediately.
不过他到乡下送货 没办法立即提供视频
He didn't know how to send the data either.
想请他把档案传过来 他也说不知道要如何操作
So, my paralegal…
所以我的律师助理…
My…
我的…
My partner, a paralegal,
我的伙伴 律师助理
rushed over there to pick up the footage.
直接冲去跟他拿视频
However, I feared that she may not make it to the trial
不过我担心在审理结束之前 她赶不回来
and decided to stall a little just now.
所以刚刚稍微争取了一点时间
If you follow the cross-examination and questioning on this script,
只要按照这个剧本 对被告进行交互讯问
your sister should have a lot to say. So take a moment to show her gratitude.
你姐姐一定会对你提出指责 趁这时候向她说声谢谢吧
Thanks to you…
多亏了你
I was able to buy a lot of time.
让我争取到不少时间
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Thus, I would like to submit this data as evidence--
因此 我想提出这个档案做为证据
One moment please.
请等一下
Such footage with unknown details is obviously unacceptable--
要拿这种细节不明的视频来讯问 我无法接受…
Please decide that after you watch it.
请你看过之后再做判断
You could end up falsely accusing someone.
再这样下去可能会造成冤案
Then the prosecutor can give their opinion after watching it.
那就请检察官看过视频之后 再提出意见
We'll decide if it's acceptable or not after that.
在那之后 再决定是否采纳这项证据
Kazuna rushed over to him.
一奈小姐立刻赶到他身边
Mr. Shinjo is waving his hand in refusal.
新庄先生挥手表示拒绝
She seems to be talking on her phone.
一奈小姐好像在打电话
Emi…
绘实小姐…
Kazuna looks like she's trying to call an ambulance.
一奈小姐看起来是想要叫救护车的
It is very clear that the defendant did not violate her duty of care.
很明显可以看到 被告并没有违反救助义务
On the other hand,
另一方面
I'd say this is the most decisive evidence of the victim's false testimony.
这也是受害者做伪证的决定性证据
She's here.
她出来了
TOKYO DETENTION CENTER
（东京拘留所）
Sis!
姐姐
Kazuna.
一奈
I believed in you.
我一直都相信你
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm glad your bail was granted immediately.
幸好保释很快就通过了
But I doubt you'd be acquitted.
不过恐怕无法争取到无罪
That's fine.
这样就够了
I lost my family to an accident.
我明明因为车祸而失去家人
And yet, I was unmindful of the fact that I could kill someone.
却对可能夺去人命的事情 一点自觉也没有
I'm really sorry.
我深切反省
I'll do the best I can for the civil compensation too.
民事赔偿我会尽量努力的
And I'll continue to support you.
我也会继续协助你们
The revised law is expected to take effect within two years
修正过的法律预计两年内就会施行
and those over 16 years old will be allowed to ride electric scooters
年满16岁 骑乘时速20公里以下的电动代步车
without a license and a helmet, if it's up to 20km/hr.
不需驾照 也不用戴安全帽
Most likely, the number of accidents will increase.
这样的意外恐怕还会继续增加
I hope more people will be aware
正因为是这么容易使用的交通工具
that they could end up killing someone
希望有更多人能意识到
because it's an easy vehicle to ride.
电动代步车也是会出人命的
I'm relieved
幸好
their child didn't have to go through what we did.
他们的孩子 不用经历跟我们一样的痛苦
The defendant is sentenced to two years in prison.
判处被告两年有期徒刑
The execution of this sentence will be suspended for three years.
自此判决宣告后缓刑三年
In addition, the defendant is acquitted of the second indictment of
此外 违反道路交通法的第二项起诉
violation of the Road Traffic Act.
宣判无罪
Oh, yeah.
对了
That job interview.
上次面试
I didn't get it.
我没通过
I'm sorry.
很遗憾
No need to rush.
不要着急
You're doing more than what we pay you to do.
既然付了工钱 就是要你努力工作
Really?
真的吗？
So hot. Something's wrong with Japan.
热死了 日本到底怎么了？
Where's Yoshio?
佳男呢？
He's coming in the afternoon today.
他今天下午才会进来
What?
什么？
I see. Then I'll come by some other time.
我明白了 那我下次再来
Here. It's Kisaburo's baumkuchen.
这是黄三郎的年轮蛋糕
-Thank you very much. -Sure. I'm gonna go.
-谢谢 -那我先走了
-Man… -Ma'am.
-搞什么… -女士
Could it be that
该不会是
you knew about the illegal casino store all along?
你一开始就知道非法赌场的事？
You wanted to expose that casino group.
你很想曝光那个非法赌场
But if a relative of the prosecutor is a regular there,
但是有检方的亲戚经常出入
the higher-ups may cover it up.
高层很可能会因此而吃官司
Because prosecutors are too soft on their family.
因为检方对自己人很宽容
Therefore, you led us to expose that store
所以你故意让我们查出内情
so the police will have to take action.
逼得警方不得不出动
In fact, there was a raid after the trial, wasn't there?
事实上 在诉讼结束后 那间赌场遭到大规模扫荡了吧？
Takanobu Shinjo was arrested too.
新庄隆信也被逮捕了
So, as I said, this trial was all your--
也就是说 这次的审判全在你的…
Hang on a second. What is this? Is this a courtroom?
等一下 现在是怎样？ 这里是法庭吗？
Am I being interrogated?
我是在接受审问吗？
You know, you're a strange one.
你真是个怪人
Well, it might suit him better.
不过这样跟那家伙比较合得来吧
Please take care of my little brother.
我弟弟就麻烦你照顾了
She brought us something yummy!
这蛋糕看起来好好吃
-Dad! -Don't call me dad.
-爸爸 -不要叫我爸爸
I need your help!
请帮帮我
We might sue someone!
我可能要起诉某人了
Your neighbor's plum tree branch has been growing into your yard for years.
邻居的梅子树长到这边的庭院来 每年都造成困扰
My uncle's been sued!
我舅舅被告了
She's demanding 500,000 yen in compensation.
她要求50万日圆的赔偿金
When I get the job, I'm going to ask you out.
等我找到工作就约你出来
You two stay put.
你俩别插手
Please wait. I don't understand.
请等一下 我不明白
-Stay here. -Why won't you let me…
-待在这里 -为什么不让我…
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo
字幕翻译：赤焰